Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another great lesson about appointments.
今天我们要带来另一节关于预约的精彩课程。
That's right.
没错。
We've got an elementary lesson about cancelling an appointment.
我们有一节关于取消预约的基础课程。
It's a really common situation sometimes.
这有时是很常见的情况。
You have an appointment at the doctor's or something.
比如你在医生那里有个预约之类的。
Or at work.
或者工作上的。
And you have to cancel it.
然后你不得不取消它。
Yes.
是的。
So we're going to learn some great language to help you cancel appointments today.
所以今天我们将学习一些很棒的语言来帮你取消预约。
Let's go straight to the dialogue then.
那我们直接进入对话吧。
We're going to be listening as Samantha and Angela have a phone conversation.
我们将听到Samantha和Angela通电话。
And Angela is trying to cancel an appointment.
Angela正试图取消一个预约。
And it's going to be a little bit fast in the beginning.
一开始语速会有点快。
But when we come back, we will explain all the great vocabulary.
但等我们回来，会解释所有重要的词汇。
Hello, Samantha speaking.
你好，我是Samantha。
Hi, Samantha.
嗨，Samantha。
This is Angela calling.
我是Angela。
Oh, hi, Angela.
哦，嗨，Angela。
What's up?
怎么了？
I'm just calling about our meeting today.
我打电话来是关于我们今天的会议。
I wonder, is it possible to reschedule our appointment in the afternoon?
我想知道，能不能把下午的预约改个时间？
I have a bit of an emergency that I need to take care of.
我有点急事需要处理。
Let me see.
让我想想。
It shouldn't be too much of a problem.
应该没什么大问题。
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉。
I hope it doesn't inconvenience you too much.
希望没有给你带来太多不便。
It's just this thing came up and...
只是突然出了点事……
Angela, you know what?
Angela，你知道吗？
I can't make it to our meeting either.
我也去不了我们的会议了。
Why don't we postpone it to tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
我们不如把它推迟到明天下午同一时间？
Sounds great.
听起来不错。
See you tomorrow.
明天见。
Angela, look up.
Angela，抬头看。
See that lady over there who's trying on a red leather jacket?
看到那边那个正在试穿红色皮夹克的女士了吗？
Isn't that Samantha?
那不是Samantha吗？
What?
什么？
No wonder she told me she couldn't make it to the meeting.
难怪她告诉我她来不了会议了。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
I think she saw me.
我觉得她看见我了。
Okay, we have some really interesting words that you probably listened to in this dialogue.
好的，我们有一些非常有趣的单词，你可能在这个对话中听到了。
So let's start with language takeaway.
那么我们从语言要点开始吧。
Today on language takeaway, we're bringing you three words.
今天的语言要点，我们带来三个单词。
Erica, what's the first one?
埃里卡，第一个是什么？
The first word is reschedule.
第一个单词是 reschedule。
Reschedule.
Reschedule。
重新安排。
When you reschedule an appointment, you...
当你重新安排一个约会时，你...
Change it for another day or time.
把它改到另一天或另一个时间。
Exactly.
没错。
Great.
很好。
The second word that we have is inconvenience.
我们要学的第二个词是不便。
Inconvenience.
不便。
So, to inconvenience someone is to...
所以，给某人带来不便就是...
To make things not convenient for that person.
为了让那个人不方便。
Right.
对。
So, to make things a little bit difficult or to make things a little bit...
所以，让事情变得有点困难，或者让事情变得有点……
Uncomfortable.
不舒服。
Inconvenience.
不便。
And our third word is...
我们的第三个词是……
Postpone.
推迟。
We have some examples of the word postpone that will help you to understand its meaning
我们有一些关于“推迟”这个词的例子，可以帮助你更好地理解它的意思。
a little bit better.
稍微好一点。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example 1.
例子1。
Since Robert is late again, we have to postpone the meeting.
由于罗伯特又迟到了，我们不得不推迟会议。
Example 2.
例子2。
I'm sorry, Simon, but your vacation has been postponed until next month.
对不起，西蒙，你的假期被推迟到下个月了。
Example 3.
例子3。
Unfortunately, the flight will be postponed.
不幸的是，航班将被推迟。
Okay, so basically postpone is to delay.
好的，基本上postpone就是推迟的意思。
That's right.
没错。
Make it at a later time.
改到更晚的时间。
At a later time.
更晚的时间。
Okay, some great words there and we can listen to our dialogue a second time at a slower
好的，这里有一些很棒的词，我们可以用较慢的速度再听一遍对话。
speed.
速度。
Hello, Samantha speaking.
你好，我是萨曼莎。
Hi, Samantha.
嗨，萨曼莎。
This is Angela calling.
我是安吉拉。
Oh, hi, Angela.
哦，嗨，安吉拉。
What's up?
怎么了？
I'm just calling about our meeting today.
我打电话来是关于今天会议的事。
I wonder, is it possible to reschedule our appointment in the afternoon?
我想问一下，下午的预约能不能改期？
I have a bit of an emergency that I need to take care of.
我有点急事需要处理。
Let me see.
让我想想。
It shouldn't be too much of a problem.
应该问题不大。
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉。
I hope it doesn't inconvenience you too much.
希望没有给你带来太多不便。
It's just this thing came up and…
只是突然出了点事……
Angela, you know what?
安吉拉，你知道吗？
I can't make it to our meeting either.
我也去不了我们的会议了。
Why don't we postpone it to tomorrow afternoon at the same time?
不如我们把它推迟到明天下午同一时间？
Sounds great.
听起来不错。
See you tomorrow.
明天见。
Angela, Angela, look up.
安吉拉，安吉拉，抬头看。
See that lady over there who's trying on a red leather jacket?
看到那边那位正在试穿红色皮夹克的女士了吗？
Isn't that Samantha?
那不是萨曼莎吗？
What?
什么？
No wonder she told me she couldn't make it to the meeting.
难怪她告诉我她来不了会议了。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
I think she saw me.
我觉得她看见我了。
Alright, so in this dialogue, we had some really great phrases that we should look at
好的，在这个对话中，我们有一些非常棒的短语，需要在流利度构建器中看看。
in Fluency Builder.
在流利度构建器中。
We have three phrases for you today in Fluency Builder, and the first one is so common.
今天在流利度构建器中我们准备了三个短语，第一个非常常见。
It's a great phrase.
这是一个很棒的短语。
What's up?
怎么了？
So, this is a very common way of saying hi.
这是一种非常常见的打招呼方式。
Yeah.
是的。
What's up?
怎么了？
How's it going?
最近怎么样？
What's going on?
怎么了？
Right, and now the interesting thing is that many people don't know how to answer this phrase.
对，现在有趣的是很多人不知道如何回答这个短语。
Yes, I see this all the time with my students.
是的，我经常看到我的学生这样。
So, if you say what's up, you should say…
所以，如果你说“what's up”，你应该说……
Not much.
没什么。
Nothing.
So, what's up?
那么，怎么了？
Not much.
没什么。
Alright, so the next time someone tells you what's up, now you know what to answer.
好了，下次有人对你说“what's up”，现在你知道怎么回答了。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, our second phrase is can't make it.
好的，我们的第二个短语是“can't make it”。
Can't make it.
去不了。
I can't make it.
我去不了。
We use this phrase when we want to say I cannot attend.
当我们想说“我不能参加”时，就用这个短语。
I cannot make it.
我去不了。
Yeah, I can't come.
对，我来不了。
Right, so if you're having a party today, I say, oh, I'm sorry, I can't make it.
没错，如果你今天开派对，我会说，哦，抱歉，我去不了。
It means I can't go.
意思是我不能去。
Exactly.
正是。
Maybe one more example.
也许再举一个例子。
So, Marco, we've got a meeting today at three o'clock.
那么，Marco，我们今天三点有个会议。
I can't make it.
我去不了。
I'm recording today.
我今天要录音。
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
So, can't make it.
所以，“can't make it”。
Our last word for fluency builder, this thing came up.
我们流利度训练中的最后一个词是“this thing came up”。
This thing came up.
突然有事。
This is a great way of giving an excuse for why you can't make it to an event.
这是一个很好的借口，解释你为什么不能参加某个活动。
Right.
对。
So, I can't make it today because this thing came up.
所以，我今天去不了，因为突然有事。
Like, something…
比如，某事……
Something happened.
发生了什么事。
Yeah.
是的。
Let's listen to a few examples of this phrase so we can see how it's used in the wild.
我们来听几个这个短语的例子，看看它在实际中如何使用。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm sorry that I'm late, this thing came up at work and I had to stay to take care of it.
抱歉我迟到了，工作上突然出了点事，我不得不留下来处理。
Example two.
第二个例子。
I can't talk right now.
我现在不能说话。
Something came up.
出了点事。
Example three.
第三个例子。
Sorry I missed the meeting.
抱歉我错过了会议。
Something came up.
出了点事。
Okay, great example and I guess it's perfectly clear now.
好的，很好的例子，我想现在完全清楚了。
Yes.
是的。
So, let's listen to our dialogue a third time and now we're ready to understand everything.
那么，让我们第三次听对话，现在我们准备好理解所有内容了。
I'm really sorry.
我真的很抱歉。
I hope it doesn't inconvenience you too much.
希望没有给你带来太多不便。
It's just this thing came up and…
只是出了点事，然后……
Sounds great.
听起来不错。
So, Erica, have you ever cancelled an appointment like this under false pretenses?
那么，Erica，你有没有以虚假理由取消过这样的约会？
So, for a fake reason?
就是编个假理由？
For a fake reason to go shopping?
编个假理由去购物？
I may not have told my boss so I can't make it to a meeting because this thing came up
我可能没有告诉老板我不能参加会议是因为出了点事，
and then I really was going shopping.
然后我其实去购物了。
I've never done that.
我从来没做过那种事。
But how about you, Marco?
那你呢，Marco？
Well, you know, in Ecuador, soccer is a really big thing.
嗯，你知道，在厄瓜多尔，足球是一件非常重要的事。
Right.
对。
So, when we were playing in the World Cup, Ecuador was playing and…
所以，当我们参加世界杯时，厄瓜多尔在比赛，然后……
Not you, but…
不是你，但是……
Well, no, like the Ecuadorian soccer team.
嗯，不，是厄瓜多尔足球队。
I cancelled an appointment because I was going to go watch the game.
我取消了一个约会，因为我打算去看比赛。
Really?
真的吗？
A business appointment.
一个商务约会。
Well, I guess that's okay.
嗯，我想那还行吧。
Yeah, I mean, it was like the first time we were ever in the World Cup and, you know,
是啊，我的意思是，那是我们第一次参加世界杯，你知道，
my boss didn't really put up much of a fight because I guess he also wanted to go watch the game.
我老板也没怎么反对，因为我想他也想去看比赛。
So, very similar to the events in this dialogue.
所以，和这个对话中的情况非常相似。
Very similar.
非常相似。
I guess that's kind of the inspiration behind it.
我想这就是它的灵感来源。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
I hope you found some of these phrases helpful and useful.
希望你们觉得这些短语有用。
And remember, if you have any questions about anything you heard in today's lesson,
记住，如果对今天课程中听到的内容有任何疑问，
please visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Right.
好的。
There you'll be able to find more resources and also a large community to interact with.
在那里你可以找到更多资源，还有一个大型社区可以互动。
Yes, including me and Marco.
是的，包括我和马可。
Right.
好的。
So, we'll see you there.
那么，我们到时候见。
Until then, it's…
在那之前，就是……
Bye.
再见。